前剧提要
双语特效字幕
百度贴吧衣柜字幕组
专注GOT剧集 华语冰火最专业字幕
翻译   barossa
翻译   艾莉娅的缝衣针
翻译   盗墓奸尸
君临 King's Landing
翻译   麻绳力攻
红堡
Red Keep
校对   pksunking
校对   夏大猫子
龙石岛 Dragonstone
恐怖堡 Dreadfort
临冬城 Winterfell
监制   北落师门
后期    Jeremy
策划   baozhenyuawabi
特别顾问   屈畅(ccxx)@史诗图书
绝境长城 the Wall
最专业的华语冰火资料站：冰与火之歌中文维基
http://zh.asoiaf.wikia.com/
百度冰与火之歌贴吧  &  百度权力的游戏贴吧    联合出品
弥林Meereen
根据长篇小说
《冰与火之歌》 改编
原著  乔治·R·R·马丁
权力的游戏
第四季 第一集
衣柜字幕组
史诗图书 正统奇幻的圣殿
更多冰火奇幻咨询 关注黑城堡微信平台
第一集  Two Swords
双剑
詹姆·兰尼斯特
“弑君者” 御林铁卫队长
完美无瑕
Magnificent.
看起来像是新锻造的
Looks fresh-forged.
是的
It is.
自从瓦雷利亚的末日浩劫之后
No one's made a Valyrian steel sword
就没人锻造瓦雷利亚钢了
since the Doom of Valyria.
这世上仍有三位铁匠
There are three living smiths
知道锻造瓦雷利亚钢的方法
who know how to rework Valyrian steel.
而我将其中最出色的那位
The finest of them was in Volantis.
从瓦兰提斯请来了君临
Came here to King's Landing at my invitation.
泰温·兰尼斯特
凯岩城公爵 国王之手
这么多瓦雷利亚钢你是怎么弄到手的
Where did you get this much Valyrian steel?
从已经不需要它们的人那里
From someone who no longer had need of it.
你一直都渴望我们家族也能有一把这样的剑
You've wanted one of these in the family for a long time.
- 而我们现在有两把了 - 两把？
- And now we have two. - Two?
原来的那把剑真是大的出奇
The original weapon was absurdly large.
锻造两把剑还绰绰有余
Plenty of steel for two swords.
谢谢 真是莫大的荣幸
Well, thank you. It's glorious.
你的左手得多练练
You'll have to train your left hand.
任何一个像样的剑士都不止会用一只手
Any decent swordsman knows how to use both hands.
你永远都不可能像以前一样厉害了
You'll never be as good.
确实
No.
不过只要我比其他人都强
But as long as I'm better than everyone else,
那就够了
I suppose it doesn't matter.
你只有一手 已经不能再当御林铁卫了
You can't serve in the Kingsguard with one hand.
哪个条例规定的？ 我可以 而且我一定要当
Where's that written? I can and I will.
御林铁卫宣誓终身效忠
The Kingsguard oath is for life.
战争已结束 国王现在安全了
The war is over. The king is safe.
国王永远都不安全
The king is never safe.
光是这座城里就有多少人期待看到他的头被挑在枪尖上？
How many people in this city alone would love to see his head on a pike?
你被关的时候也有别的铁卫保护国王
Other knights protected the king while you were a prisoner.
你回家以后他们也将继续执行这个任务
They will continue to do so when you go home.
- 家？ - 你将回去凯岩城
- Home? - You'll return to Casterly Rock
接替我的统治
and rule in my stead.
你才是凯岩城领主
You are the Lord of Casterly Rock.
我是国王之手 我属于这儿
I am the King's Hand. My place is here.
这辈子我已经不打算再回凯岩城了
I don't expect to see the Rock again before I die.
你知道他们是怎么叫我的？
You know what they call me?
弑君者 背誓者
Kingslayer. Oathbreaker.
毫无荣誉感的人
Man without honor.
现在你又要我再次打破一个神圣的誓言
Now you want me to break another sacred vow.
你不需要打破任何誓言
You won't be breaking anything.
御林铁卫的替换早有先例
There is a precedent to relieve a Kingsguard of his duties.
国王将会行使这项特权
The king will exercise that prerogative.
- 不 - 不？
- No. - No?
不
No.
我想我不是在征求你的意见
I don't believe I asked you a question.
这就是我的回答
There's my answer.
你要是觉得你那些该死的荣誉比——
If you think your bloody honor comes before--
我那些该死的荣誉早已无法挽回
My bloody honor is beyond repair,
但我的答案依然是 不 我不想要凯岩城
but my answer is still no. I don't want Casterly Rock.
我不想要妻子 我不想要孩子
I don't want a wife. I don't want children.
你要什么
What do you want?
不如来顿晚餐
Supper would be nice.
四十年了 我一直都在试着教你
For 40 years I've tried to teach you.
如果你至今都没有开窍 那你永远都不会了
If you haven't learned by now, you never will.
走吧
Go.
如果当个光荣的侍卫
If serving as a glorified bodyguard
就是你的全部野心了 那就去服务吧
is the sum of your ambition, go serve.
我猜你要我把剑还给你
I suppose you want the sword back.
留着吧
Keep it.
对于一个不需要家庭的单手男人来说
A one-handed man with no family needs
这就是他能得到的最大帮助了
all the help he can get.
提利昂·兰尼斯特
“小恶魔” 财政大臣
波隆
骑士
波德瑞克·派恩
提利昂的侍从
就算是干山羊也得好几个多恩人一起上吧？
How many Dornishmen does it take to fuck a goat?
别说了
Please don't.
要我说 见远程而来的人
Seems to me the smart place
最好的地方应该是酒馆
to meet travelers is in a tavern.
这样的话 要是一方迟到了
That way, one party is late,
另一方还能在里面喝点麦芽酒
the other party can drink some ale inside.
我们等的可是多恩亲王
This is the Prince of Dorne we're waiting for,
又不是你的佣兵朋友
not one of your sellsword friends.
要是他真他妈的这么重要 干嘛要你来接见他？
If he's so damned important, how come they sent you to meet him?
多恩的马泰尔家族和凯岩城的兰尼斯特家族
There's bad blood between the Martells of Dorne
之间有多年的血仇
and the Lannisters of Casterly Rock. Has been for years.
所以万一多恩的马泰尔家
And just in case the Martells of Dorne
想要洒点兰尼斯特家的血的话
are looking to spill some Lannister blood,
- 最好是你的 恩？ - 没必要挖苦我
- it may as well be yours, eh? - No need for cynicism.
我不巧是个很有手腕的外交官罢了
I happen to be an accomplished diplomat.
他们来了
here we are.
能看见家徽么？
Can you read the sigils?
几个黄色的蛋？
Yellow balls?
紫色底上有黄色的柠檬
Wild lemons on a purple field,
柠檬林的达特家族
House Dalt of Lemonwood.
一只抓着婴孩的秃鹫 布莱蒙家族
A vulture grasping a baby in its talons, House Blackmont.
一个头戴王冠的骷髅 曼伍迪家族
A crowned skull, the Manwoodys of Kingsgrave.
你对多恩家族了如指掌啊
Boy knows his Dornish Houses.
我也需要个家徽
I need a sigil.
还有马泰尔家族 家徽是长枪贯日？
And House Martell, a red sun pierced by a spear?
我没看见 大人
I don't see it, my lord.
幸会 大人们
Well met, my lords.
乔佛里陛下欢迎您们的到来
His Grace King Joffrey welcomes you in his name.
同时我也替我的父亲大人 国王之手 致以深切的问候
My lord father, the King's Hand, sends his greetings as well.
我是财政大臣
I am Tyrion Lannister of Casterly Rock,
凯岩城的提利昂·兰尼斯特
Master of Coin.
请原谅
Forgive me.
我并未看到道朗亲王与你们同行
I don't see Prince Doran in your company.
亲王身体不适 只能留于阳戟城
The prince's health forces him to remain at Sunspear.
他派来了弟弟奥柏伦亲王
He sends his brother Prince Oberyn
代替他来参加国王的婚礼
to attend the royal wedding in his stead.
好的 像奥柏伦亲王这样久负盛名的战士
Yes, the king will be delighted to enjoy the company
能来参加婚礼 陛下一定会
of a warrior as renowned as Prince Oberyn
非常高兴的
at his wedding feast.
他会么？
Will he?
奥柏伦亲王在哪儿呢？
And where is Prince Oberyn?
他已于破晓前抵达了
Arrived before dawn.
我们的亲王
Not a man for welcome parties,
不喜欢这些繁文缛节
our prince.
那好吧 大人们 这些都城守备队员
Very well. My lords, these fine men from the City Watch
将会护送您们去红堡中的住处
will escort you to your quarters in the Red Keep.
远道而来 您们一定也疲倦了
You must be weary after such a long journey.
刚才那是很有手腕的外交技巧？
Some accomplished diplomacy that was.
现在去哪儿？
Now where?
我们得赶紧找到奥柏伦亲王 以防他闹出人命
We must find Prince Oberyn before he kills somebody
或者闹出好几条人命
or several somebodies.
这么大的城 上哪儿找一个多恩人去？
How do you plan on finding a single Dornishman in a city this big?
都说你操过半个维斯特洛的妞
You're famous for fucking half of Westeros.
你在个破路上颠簸了两周了才刚到首都
You just arrived at the capital after two weeks of bad roads,
你会去哪儿？
where would you go?
我没准就去睡觉了 不过我有点上年纪了
I'd probably go to sleep, but I'm getting old.
奥柏伦·纳梅洛斯·马泰尔
“红毒蛇” 多恩亲王
看看这个
Look at this one.
她多可爱
How lovely is she?
美丽
Beautiful.
但苍白
But pale.
在首都 人们就好这口儿
They like them pale in the capital.
说明他们不必下地干活儿
Shows they don't work the fields.
艾拉莉亚·沙德
奥柏伦的情妇
我吓着你了吗？
Do I frighten you?
你喜欢吗？
You like?
害羞 太害羞让我觉得无趣
Timid. Timid bores me.
你比较调皮 是不是？
You're a bit of mischief, aren't you?
我觉得她喜欢你
I think she likes you.
她品味不错
She has good taste.
你一点也不害羞 是不是？
You're not timid, are you?
不害羞
Not timid.
你喜欢女人吗？
Do you like women?
只要她们都像她一样美 大人
When they look like her, my lord.
这个一定会干的不错
This one will do nicely.
太好了 夫人
Very good, my lady.
我可不是什么夫人
Oh, I'm not a lady.
在我们这儿 这只是礼貌用语
A term of courtesy in this establishment.
无论在哪儿都是谎言
A lie anywhere.
我们干嘛不用点正确的词汇？
Why not use the right words?
我是个私生女
I'm a bastard.
她是个婊子 你是什么？
She is a whore. And you're what?
一个拉皮条的
A procurer.
还要别人吗？
Any of the others?
这两个女孩可以走了
The two girls can leave.
你留下
You stay.
我恐怕我不在出售之列 大人
I'm afraid I'm not an offer, my lord.
所有替小指头卖命的人都能出售
Everyone who works for Littlefinger is an offer.
脱衣服 我们要在这儿待很久
Take off your clothes. We'll be here a while.
- 大人 - 我是个亲王 孩子
- My lord. - I am a prince, boy.
你跟亲王睡过吗？
Have you ever been with a prince?
我想没有吧
Can't say I have.
我可是很贵的
I'm wildly expensive.
脱掉你的衣服
Take off your clothes.
你喜欢按什么方式玩？
Which way do you like it?
我的方式
My way.
噢他这样说 他这样说
And so he spoke and so he spoke
卡斯特梅的爵爷
That Lord of Castamere
- 奥柏伦 - 然而今天 每逢雨季……
- Oberyn. - And now the rains...
- 奥柏伦 不要 - 雨水在大厅哭泣
- Oberyn, don't. - Weep o'er his hall...
内里却无人影
With no one there to hear
然而今天 每逢雨季 雨水在大厅哭泣
Yes, not the rains weep o'er his hall
内里却无魂灵
And not a soul to hear.
你迷路了 朋友？
You lost, friend?
原谅我这样盯着你们
Forgive me for staring.
我们那儿没见过什么兰尼斯特的人
I don't see many Lannisters where I'm from.
我在首都也没见过多恩人
I don't see many Dornishmen in the capital.
我们不喜欢这股味道
We don't like the smell.
- 跟我来 情人 - 天哪 看看这个
- Come with me, lover. - Gods, look at this one.
先生们 如果你们跟我来 我会给你们一个单间
Sirs, if you follow me, I'll arrange for a private room.
你们干嘛把这么好一个女人浪费在多恩人身上？
Why are you wasting a woman like this on a Dornishman?
给他头剃光了的山羊还有一瓶橄榄油就行了
Bring him a shaved goat and a bottle of olive oil.
你们知道为什么全世界都讨厌兰尼斯特吗？
Do you know why all the world hates a Lannister?
你们觉得你们的金币和狮子
You think your gold and your lions
还有你们的金狮子就能让你们比任何人都强了
and your gold lions make you better than everyone.
不如我告诉你们一个秘密吧
May I tell you a secret?
你们根本不是金狮子
You're not a golden lion.
你们就是些小娘娘腔
You're just a pink little man
拔剑慢得要命
who is far too slow on the draw.
近身战 长剑可不好使
Longsword is a bad option in close quarters.
我只要一拔匕首 你的朋友就会开始流血
When I pull my blade, your friend starts bleeding.
我恐怕会血流不止 手腕上有太多血管了
Quite a lot, I'm afraid. So many veins in the wrist.
要是你立刻帮忙的话他就能活命
He'll live if you get him help straightaway.
做决定吧
So, decisions.
奥柏伦亲王 请原谅 打搅了
Prince Oberyn, forgive the intrusion.
我们听见好像有...
We heard there might be...
...麻烦
...trouble.
抱歉 我的爱人
Apologies, my love.
我来这儿是为了欢迎您到君临来
I'm here to welcome you to the capital.
这位是艾拉利亚·沙德 我的情人
Ellaria Sand, my paramour.
这位是国王的亲舅舅 小恶魔
The king's own Uncle Imp.
泰温·兰尼斯特的儿子提利昂
Tyrion, son of Tywin Lannister.
如果有什么我能帮忙的 让您此行——
If there's anything I can do to make your stay--
你是谁? 他的雇佣杀手?
What are you? His hired killer?
以前是 现在我是骑士了
It started that way, aye. Now I'm a knight.
怎么成骑士了?
How did that come to pass?
我想我杀对了人
Killed the right people, I suppose.
我们还要叫些姑娘来 是姑娘 对吧?
We'll need a few more girls. Girls, yes?
你不加入吗?
You don't partake?
以前会 现在我结婚了
Oh, I partook. Now I'm married.
奥柏伦亲王 我想跟您单独谈谈 可以吗?
Prince Oberyn, if I may, a word in private?
我好像误闯了兰尼斯特家的妓院啊
Seems I visited the Lannister brothel by mistake.
- 哦 他们什么人都接的 - 连多恩人都接
- Oh, they take all kinds. - Even Dornishmen.
国王感谢您能远道而来
The king is very grateful that you traveled all
参加他的婚礼
this way for his wedding.
我们说实话吧 乔佛里感觉被侮辱了
Let us speak truth here. Joffrey is insulted.
毕竟我只是次子
I am only the second son after all.
好吧 这样说的话 我也是次子
Well, speaking as a fellow second son,
我已经习惯了被当作家族的耻辱
I have grown rather used to being the family insult.
奥柏伦亲王 您为何要到君临来?
Why did you come to King's Landing, Prince Oberyn?
我受邀来参加皇家婚礼
I was invited to the royal wedding.
我以为我们在说实话
I thought we were speaking truth.
上次我来君临还是很多年以前
The last time I was in the capital was many years ago.
参加另一场婚礼
Another wedding.
是我姐姐伊莉亚
My sister Elia
和最后的真龙传人雷加·坦格利安的婚礼
and Rhaegar Targaryen, the Last Dragon.
我姐姐爱他 她为他生孩子
My sister loved him. She bore his children.
她亲自给孩子们喂奶 哄他们睡着
Swaddled them, rocked them, fed them at her own breast.
伊莉亚不让奶妈碰孩子
Elia wouldn't let the wet nurse touch them.
而英俊高贵的雷加·坦格利安
And beautiful, noble Rhaegar Targaryen
却为了另一个女人离开了她
left her for another woman.
这引发了一场战争
That started a war
而那场战争就是在这里结束的
and the war ended right here
你父亲的军队占领了城市
when your father's army took the city...
我不在场
I wasn't actually present.
...还屠杀了那些孩子们
...and butchered those children.
我的外甥和外甥女
My nephew and niece.
杀死他们 然后用兰尼斯特家族的斗篷包起来
Carved them up and wrapped them in Lannister cloaks.
我姐姐 你知道他们是怎么对她的?
And my sister, you know what they did to her?
我问你呢
I'm asking you a question.
我听到了一些传言
I've heard rumors.
我也听到了
So have I.
我听到最多的传言是魔山格雷果·克里冈
The one I keep hearing is that Gregor Clegane the Mountain
强奸了伊莉亚 然后用他的剑
raped Elia and split her in half
把她砍成两半
with his great sword.
我不在场 我不知道发生了什么
I wasn't there. I don't know what happened.
如果是魔山杀死了我姐姐
If the Mountain killed my sister,
那就是你父亲下的命令
your father gave the order.
告诉你父亲 我在这里
Tell your father I'm here.
告诉他“有债必偿”的并不只有兰尼斯特家
And tell him the Lannisters aren't the only ones who pay their debts.
丹妮莉丝·坦格利安
风暴降生 龙之母
卓耿
丹妮莉丝·坦格利安的龙
嘘
Shh.
乔拉·莫尔蒙
“大熊” 熊老之子
嘘 嘘
Shh. Shh.
它们是龙 卡丽熙
They're dragons, Khaleesi.
它们永远无法被驯服
They can never be tamed.
即使龙母也不行
Not even by their mother.
- 巴利斯坦爵士 - 陛下
- Ser Barristan. - Your Grace.
达里奥·纳哈里斯在哪儿?
Where's Daario Naharis?
弥桑黛
丹妮莉丝·坦格利安的侍女
巴利斯坦·赛尔弥
“无畏的”女王铁卫
灰虫子在哪儿?
Where's Grey Worm?
在打赌 陛下
Gambling, Your Grace.
打赌？
Gambling?
弥莎 弥莎 弥莎
Mhysa. Mhysa. Mhysa...
他们像这样多久了?
How long have they been at it?
从午夜开始 陛下
Since midnight, Your Grace.
灰虫子爵士比看上去要强壮些
Ser Worm is stronger than he looks.
但我能看出他的胳膊开始颤抖了
But I can see his arms beginning to shake.
达里奥·纳哈里斯
前次子团成员
灰虫子
无垢者军团指挥官
赢得这场愚蠢竞赛的奖赏是什么?
What's the prize to winning this stupid contest?
获得在去弥林的路上在您身边骑行的荣耀
The honor of riding by your side on the road to Meereen.
那个荣耀属于乔拉爵士和巴利斯坦爵士
That honor goes to Ser Jorah and Ser Barristan
因为今天早上他们没让我久等
as neither of them kept me waiting this morning.
你们两个殿后 保护牲畜
You two will ride in the rear guard and protect the livestock.
最后一个举着剑的人
The last man holding his sword
重新找个女王去效忠吧
can find a new queen to fight for.
你喜欢这姑娘?
你一定很沮丧
你不是个聪明人 达里奥·纳哈里斯
我宁愿没脑子
也不要没蛋卵
珊莎·史塔克
提利昂的夫人
雪伊
珊莎的侍女 小恶魔的情人
你得吃点东西
You need to eat something.
鸽子派
Pigeon pie.
不用了 谢谢
No, thank you.
吃柠檬蛋糕吗?
Lemon cakes?
不用了 谢谢
No, thank you.
你很爱吃柠檬蛋糕
You love lemon cakes.
告诉她 她得吃东西
Tell her she needs to eat.
夫人 你真的需要吃东西
My lady, you do need to eat.
我不需要吃东西
I don't need to eat.
我想和我夫人单独待会儿
If I could have a moment alone with my wife.
她得吃东西
She needs to eat.
我不能让你饿死
I can't let you starve.
我发过誓要保护你
I swore to protect you.
夫人
My lady,
我是你丈夫 让我帮助你
I am your husband. Let me help you.
你怎么帮我?
How can you help me?
我不知道 但我可以试试
I don't know, but I can try.
我整晚失眠 盯着天花板
I lie awake all night staring at the canopy
满脑子都是他们惨死的样子
thinking about how they died.
我可以给你弄点夜影之水 有助于睡眠
I could get you essence of nightshade to help you sleep.
你知道他们对我哥哥做了什么吗?
Do you know what they did to my brother?
他们把冰原狼的脑袋缝到他身上
How they sewed his direwolf's head onto his body?
而我母亲
And my mother.
人们说他们把她喉咙割开 深可见骨
They say they cut her throat to the bone
然后将尸身扔入河中
and threw her body in the river.
你家人的遭遇是一桩可怕的罪行
What happened to your family was a terrible crime.
我不了解你哥哥
I didn't know your brother.
他看起来是个好人 但我不了解他
He seemed like a good man, but I didn't know him.
而你的母亲
Your mother, on the other hand,
我很钦佩她
I admired her.
虽然她很想弄死我
She wanted to have me executed,
但我钦佩她
but I admired her.
她是一位坚强的女子
She was a strong woman.
而当她保护自己的孩子时
And she was fierce
她是很强势的
when it came to protecting her children.
珊莎
Sansa.
你母亲会希望你活下去
Your mother would want you to carry on.
这你是知道的
You know it's true.
请原谅 大人?
Will you pardon me, my lord?
我想去神木林
I'd like to visit the godswood.
当然 当然 我听说祈祷很有用
Of course. Of course. Prayer can be helpful, I hear.
我不再祈祷了
I don't pray anymore.
只有在那儿 没人和我说话
It's the only place I can go where people don't talk to me.
我的狮子
My lion.
你在这儿干什么?
What are you doing?
你看我像在干什么? 来
What does it look like I'm doing? Come here.
我跟你说过多少次了? 你不能在这儿见我
How many times have I told you? You can't visit me here.
我知道 我知道
I know. I know.
这是个危险的地方
We have come to a dangerous place.
你忘了我吗? 你知道已经多久了吗?
Have you forgotten me? Do you know how long it's been?
我当然没忘
Of course I haven't forgotten.
我想要你
I want you.
你不想要我吗?
Don't you want me?
现在形势紧张
Things are a bit tense right now.
什么形势?
What things?
我的国王外甥想要杀死我
My nephew the king wants to murder me.
我妻子恨我 因为我父亲杀了她全家
My wife hates me because my father murdered her family.
奥柏伦·马泰尔想要杀死每一个
Oberyn Martell wants to murder everyone whose
姓兰尼斯特的人
last name is Lannister.
你需要放松一下
You need to relax.
你不想放松一下吗?
Don't you want to relax?
- 怎么了? - 我跟你说过了
- What's wrong? - I told you.
- 现在不是时候 - 永远都不是时候
- It's not a good time. - It's never a good time.
- 你现在有一个孩子做新娘了 - 雪伊
- You have your child bride now. - Shae.
- 你爱她吗? - 爱她?
- Do you love her? - Love her?
我几乎不了解她 她只是个孩子
I barely know her. She's a child.
- 她看不起我 - 这不算回答
- She despises me. - That's not an answer.
我当然不爱她
Of course I don't love her.
你想把我送走
You tried to ship me away.
送你走?
Ship you away?
你送我钻石 好让我消失
Give me diamonds and make me disappear.
你究竟在说些什么?
What in the world are you talking about?
如果你想让我走 只管说好了
If you want me to leave, just say it.
- 说! - 嘘
- Say it! - Shh.
我不明白你在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
你想让我留下来吗?
You want me to stay?
科本
被剥夺项链的学士
这真是一件艺术品
A work of art, really.
手艺太出色了
The craftsmanship is excellent.
你这么喜欢它
You like it so much,
欢迎你砍下自己的手 收下它
you're welcome to chop off your own hand and take it.
真是个忘恩负义的家伙 我和金匠花了几天时间
Such an ingrate. I spent days with the goldsmith
瑟曦·兰尼斯特
摄政太后
- 确保细节万无一失 - 几天?
- getting the details just right. - Days?
大半个下午
Better part of an afternoon.
感觉如何?
There, how does that feel?
额...
Uh...
换成钩子会更实用
a hook would be more practical.
我觉得很优雅
Elegant, I think.
关于另一件事 谢谢你的帮忙
Thank you for your help with the other matter.
- 症状消退了? - 完全消退了
- The symptoms have abated? - Gone completely.
非常感谢 科本学士
I am in your debt, Maester Qyburn.
陛下 我不是学士 但乐意效劳
Not a maester, Your Grace, but happy to help
随时找我都可以
whenever I can.
奇怪的小老头
Odd little man.
我越来越喜欢他了
I've grown rather fond of him.
你知道吗 他很有才华?
He's quite talented, you know?
什么症状?
What symptoms?
与你无关的症状
Symptoms that are not your concern.
你让他摸你了?
You let him touch you?
你嫉妒了?
You jealous?
我很吃惊
I'm surprised.
你从没让派席尔靠近你
You never let Pycelle near you.
你以为我会让那个老色鬼
You think I'd let that old lecher
把手放到我身上?
put his hands on me?
他闻起来像只死猫
He smells like a dead cat.
我不觉得自己闻过死猫
I'm not sure I've ever smelled a dead cat.
它们闻起来像派席尔
Well, they smell like Pycelle.
你比以前喝得多了
You drink more than you used to.
- 对 - 为什么?
- Yes. - Why?
让我想想 你在街上和奈德·史塔克斗殴
Let's see, you started a brawl in the streets with Ned Stark
然后从君临城消失
and disappeared from the capital.
我丈夫死于一次悲剧的打猎事故
My husband died in a tragic hunting accident.
你一定很痛苦
It must have been traumatic for you.
我唯一的女儿被送往多恩
My only daughter was shipped off to Dorne.
我们遭遇了一次围城
We suffered through a siege.
一次很短的围城
A rather short siege.
一次很短的围城 但我以为活不了了
A rather short siege that I didn't expect to survive.
现在我的长子即将迎娶
And now I'm marrying my eldest son
高庭那个邪恶的小婊子
to a wicked little bitch from Highgarden
而我要嫁给她的哥哥
while I'm supposed to marry her brother,
一个众人皆知的同性恋 所以...
a renowned pillow biter. So...
父亲今天和我断绝关系了
Father disowned me today.
他不能和你断绝关系 他只有你
He can't disown you. You're all he's got.
你忘了提利昂
You're forgetting Tyrion.
你不会真打算留在御林铁卫中吧?
You don't really plan on staying in the Kingsguard, do you?
留在御林铁卫中就意味着我可以住在这里
Staying in the Kingsguard means I live right here
和你一起待在红堡里
in the Red Keep with you.
- 现在不行 - 我想——
- Not now. - I want--
现在不行? 那什么时候? 我都回来几周了
Not now? When? I've been back for weeks.
- 有些东西变了 - 一切都变了
- Something's changed. - Everything's changed.
你离开了这么久 回来连句道歉的话都没有
You come back after all this time with no apologies
而且只剩了一只手 怎么能指望一切都和原来一样?
and one hand and expect everything to be the same?
你要我道什么歉?
What do you want me to apologize for?
因为你离开了我
For leaving me.
你以为我想当俘虏?
You think I wanted to be taken prisoner?
我不知道你想要什么 当时你不在
Don't know what you wanted. You weren't here.
你丢下我一人独自面对
You left me alone.
在被囚禁的每一天里 每一天我都在计划着逃跑
Every day I was a prisoner, I plotted my escape.
我曾为了为能与你重聚不惜杀人
Every day. I murdered people so I could be here with you.
- 你花的时间太久 - 我……
- You took too long. - I...
- 你说什么？ - 我说你花的时间太久
- What are you saying? - I'm saying you took too long.
- 进来 - 退下
- Come in. - Go away.
抱歉 太后陛下
Forgive me, Your Grace.
您告诉我一有要事就即刻向您禀报
You told me to come at once if there was anything important.
耶哥蕊特
“火吻而生” 野人
托蒙德
“巨人克星” 野人
你打算一个人杀光所有的乌鸦？
You plan on killing all the crows yourself?
那你是打算干坐着挠鸡巴等冬天来？
Do you plan on sitting here scratching your balls till winter?
我们等曼斯的命令
We wait for Mance's orders.
你在满月的时派了人去侦察长城
You sent a man over the Wall at the full moon.
如果他到现在还没回来 那就再也不会回来了
If he's not back yet, he's not coming back.
你打算怎么做？
And what is it you want?
就带着这点人进军黑城堡？
March on Castle Black with just this lot?
你那漂亮的小乌鸦说那里驻扎着一千人
Your pretty crow said 1,000 men are nesting there.
是啊 但他是个骗子
Yeah, well, he's a liar.
他是吗？
He is?
不应该说“他曾是”吗？
Shouldn't it be "he was"?
你说你射了他三箭
You said you put three arrows in him.
是的
I did.
我见过你把箭射进二百码开外的兔子眼睛里
I've seen you slip a shaft through a rabbit's eye at 200 yards.
如果那小子还能走得动 说明你放了他一马
If that boy's still walking, it's 'cause you let him go.
瑟恩人
Thenns.
我他妈的烦死这群瑟恩人了
I fucking hate Thenns.
斯迪
瑟恩的马格拿
曼斯派你们来？
Mance sent you?
你们是怎么找到这的？
How did you find us?
你们从南面来 而不是北面
You came from the south, not the north.
绕了个道而已
Took a detour.
在路上的村庄里搞了点补给
Got some supper from a village down that way.
为何长城这边这地方的肉尝起来
Why does the meat down here taste so much better
比我们那边的要好吃的多？
than it does on our side of the Wall?
你请便
Help yourself.
或许这边所有的牲口都被喂的更好
Maybe everything's just better fed down here.
又肥又懒
Fat and lazy.
便宜了我们 不是吗？
Easier for us, hmm?
你没看到我们来？
You didn't see us coming?
弄丢了你的易形者？
Lost your warg?
还有曾在你身边的小乌鸦
And that baby crow you had with you,
也弄丢了？
lost him too?
我只回答曼斯
I'll answer to Mance.
不用回答你
I won't answer to you.
她是你的？
She yours?
我不属于任何人
I'm not anybody's.
真是皮包骨头
Too scrawny.
不像黑城堡里的那些乌鸦
Not like those crows at Castle Black.
想想他们窝在储藏食物的地方
Think of them stuck in their larders
不停往嘴里塞火腿、血肠和炖菜
stuffing their faces with ham and blood sausage
变得越来越肥美
and stew, getting nice and fat
越来越迟钝
and marbled.
我知道我们之间有分歧 托蒙德
I know we've had our differences, Tormund,
但在你死之前 就这一次
but just one time before you die,
你真应该尝尝乌鸦的滋味
you really ought to try crow.
拉弓
Draw.
放箭
Loose.
山姆威尔·塔利
守夜人事务官
上一次见他时
Last time I saw him,
还是在临冬城的庭院
he was in the courtyard at Winterfell.
他说 “下次再见到你
He said, "Next time I see you,
你就会是一身黑衣了”
you'll be all in black."
琼恩·雪诺
叛逃的乌鸦
我的一生都在嫉妒罗柏
I was jealous of Robb my whole life.
父亲看着他的那种目光
The way my father looked at him,
我也想要他用同样的目光看着我
I wanted that.
他什么都比我强
He was better than me at everything--
武艺 狩猎
fighting and hunting
骑马
and riding
吸引女孩
and girls.
诸神啊 女孩们都爱死他了
Gods, the girls loved him.
我多想恨他 但我做不到
I wanted to hate him, but I never could.
有时我也想恨你
Sometimes I want to hate you.
呃 你在所有方面都比我强
Well, you're better than me at everything.
除了读书
Except reading.
他们——他们准备好见你了
They're-- they're ready for you.
他早就想要吊死我了 现在他的机会来了
He's wanted to hang me for a while. Now's his chance.
没人会吊死你的
No one's going to hang you.
你没做过任何错事
You've done nothing wrong.
我做了太多错事
I've done plenty wrong.
你承认你谋害了半掌科林？
So you admit you murdered Qhorin Halfhand?
我没谋害他
I didn't murder him.
没有？你用你的剑
No? You put your sword
刺穿守夜人弟兄的身体
through a brother of the Night's Watch.
杰诺斯·史林特
守夜人兄弟  前都城守备队队长
艾里沙·索恩
守夜人的教头
伊蒙·坦格利安
守夜人的学士
你管那叫啥？
What do you call that?
他要我杀了他
He wanted me to kill him.
一个叛徒杂种
A bastard son of a traitor.
你还能指望啥？
What would you expect?
半掌认为我们要阻止曼斯的唯一办法
The Halfhand believed our only chance
就是在他的军中安插内应打探实情
to stop Mance was to get a man inside his army.
不要这样谈论半掌 好像你有多了解他
Don't talk about the Halfhand as if you knew him.
他曾是我的弟兄
He was my brother.
那你就该知道他会不惜一切保卫长城
Then you'd know he'd do anything to defend the Wall.
自由民本想可以他活烹 但最后却让我杀了他……
The free folk would have boiled him alive, but letting me kill him...
自由民？听听他这口气
The free folk? Listen to him.
连说话都像个野人了
He even talks like a wildling now.
是的 我说话像野人 我和野人一起吃饭
Aye, I talk like a wildling. I ate with the wildlings.
我和野人一起翻过长城 我——
I climbed the Wall with the wildlings. I--
我和野人姑娘睡觉
I laid with a wildling girl.
你承认打破了誓言？
You admit to breaking your vows, then?
我承认
I do.
律法就是律法 这个小子必须得死
The law is the law. The boy must die.
如果我们把每个跟女孩子上床的游骑兵都抓来砍头
If we beheaded every ranger who lay with a girl,
那长城只能由无头士兵来把守了
the Wall would be manned by headless men.
去鼹鼠村妓院溜个号是一码事
There's a difference between sneaking off
与敌人同床共枕又是另外一码事了
to the Mole's Town brothel and sleeping with the enemy.
就在这当口我们坐这儿
While we sit here
为我打破了那条规矩争论不休
debating which rules I broke,
而曼斯雷德正带着十万大军向长城进发
Mance Rayder marches on the Wall with an army of 100,000.
不可能
Impossible.
没有人聚起数目超过50的野人群体
You can't get 50 wildlings together
他们还没走到一起就开始互相残杀
before they start killing each other.
十万 他统一了瑟恩人
100,000. He's united the Thenns,
硬足民 冰川部落
the Hornfoots, the ice-river clans.
还有巨人为他作战
He has giants fighting for him.
巨人？
Giants?
你到过长城之外吗 爵士？
Have you ever been beyond the Wall, ser?
我指挥过君临的都城守备队 小子
I commanded the City Watch of King's Landing, boy.
而现在你在这
And now you're here.
你肯定不太擅长你的工作
You must not have been very good at your job.
大胆！
How dare you?!
长城南边已经有一队野人了
There's a band of wildlings south of the Wall already
由巨人杀手托蒙德带领
led by Tormund Giantsbane.
我杀了他们的易形者和另外三个人
I killed their warg and three others.
他们留给我满身的箭
They shot me full of arrows.
曼斯命令他们从南面进攻黑城堡
Their orders are to attack Castle Black from the south
而他在北边响应
when Mance hits it from the north.
进攻的信号是篝火
The signal for the attack will be a bonfire.
曼斯说那将会是
Mance said it would be the greatest fire
北境前所未见的大火
the North has ever seen.
这是真的
That's the truth.
我说的都是真的
All the truth.
你们是打算处决我还是放我自由？
Do you intend to execute me or am I free to go?
我们中没有人是自由的
None of us are free.
我们是守夜人
We are men of the Night's Watch.
但我们不会现在就要你的脑袋 琼恩·雪诺
But we won't be taking your head today, Jon Snow.
你走吧
Go on.
现在我是这儿的指挥官 伊蒙师傅
I am acting commander here, Maester Aemon.
是的 你是
Yes, you are.
而我不相信这个杂种
And I don't trust the bastard.
他说的都是真话
He told the truth.
你总是能知道一个人是否在说谎？
And you always know when a man's telling a lie?
你是从何处得到这种魔法的？
How did you acquire this magical power?
我在君临长大
I grew up in King's Landing.
不行 不行
No. No.
你是王后 不是公牛
You're a queen, not an ox.
你祖父在我第五十一个命名日送了条项链给我
Your grandfather gave me a necklace
奥莲娜夫人
荆棘女王
玛格丽·提利尔
乔佛里国王的未婚妻
和这条几乎一模一样
just like this one for my 51st nameday.
婚礼已经不到半个月了 祖母
The wedding is in a fortnight, Grandmother.
您不能对所有的都不满意
You can't say no to everything.
胡说 我亲爱的
Nonsense. My little dears.
去找君临的珠宝匠们谈谈
Go and speak to the jewelers of King's Landing.
告诉他们你们是谁 告诉他们谁派你们来的
Tell them who you are, tell them who sent you.
谁带给我最好的项链
The one who brings me the best necklace
我就把第二好的那条给她
will get to keep the next best.
半个月后玛格丽·提利尔走进圣堂的那一刻
The Margaery Tyrell who walks into the sept
会为歌手诗人带来灵感 作出一千首歌供人传唱
a fortnight from now will inspire 1,000 songs.
要是她戴着这样的破烂那会多令人悲伤
Now, how sad it will be if she's wearing rubbish like that.
或许我该让乔佛里替我选
Perhaps I should just let Joffrey choose it for me.
他会给我挑一串麻雀的脑袋挂在我的脖子上
End up with a string of dead sparrow heads around my neck.
你给我说话小心点 即便在此 和我一起
You watch that. Even here, even with me.
我的天哪
My word.
小姐 夫人
My lady. My lady.
请原谅我的打扰
Please pardon me for interrupting.
我是塔斯的布蕾妮
My name is Brienne of Tarth.
我们知道你是谁 我们总是听人说起你
We know who you are. We've heard all about you.
但听过是一回事
But hearing is one thing.
亲眼所见不更是了不得？
Aren't you just marvelous?
塔斯的布蕾妮
"美人"
你可真是非同一般
Absolutely singular.
我听说你把我那孙子打倒在地
I hear you knocked my grandson into the dirt
让他像个出尽洋相的傻小子
like the silly little boy he is.
小姐 我知道您现在很忙
My lady, I know this is a very busy time for you,
但是我还是想占用您一点时间
but if I could just have a moment.
你可没有拒绝她的胆子
You dare not refuse.
一个影子
A shadow?
一个有着史坦尼斯·拜拉席恩的面容的影子
A shadow with the face of Stannis Baratheon.
我以诸神的名义向您发誓那是史坦尼斯
I swear to you by all the gods it was Stannis.
他把剑穿过蓝礼的心脏
He plunged his sword through Renly's heart
然后消失不见了
and disappeared.
总有一天 小姐 我会为我们的国王报仇的
One day, my lady, I will avenge our king.
乔佛里现在是我们的国王了
Joffrey is our king now.
我无意冒犯您
I meant no offense.
你没有冒犯我
And you've given none.
乔佛里·拜拉席恩
铁王座上的王
当然了 所有御林铁卫都将出动
All the Kingsguard will be on duty, of course.
柏洛斯爵士的位置是这里
Ser Boros will be stationed here.
普列斯顿爵士的位置是这里
Ser Preston will be stationed here
在主要娱乐项目附近
beside the primary entertainment.
陛下？
Your Grace?
嗯 嗯 一名铁卫——
Yes, yes, one guard at the--
那啥 继续
the thing. Go on.
马林爵士要守护玛格丽女士和托曼
Ser Meryn will guard Lady Margaery and Tommen.
马林·特兰
御林铁卫
以前一直是由我来守护国王的 大人
I've always guarded the king himself, my lord.
自从您缺席以来
Ever since your absence.
为此我得感谢你 马林爵士
And I thank you for it, Ser Meryn.
一切好得很 我看不见得有什么麻烦
All very good. I don't expect any trouble.
民众爱戴他们的国王
The people love their king.
他们知道谁填饱了他们的肚子
They know who keeps them fed.
我听说是玛格丽·提利尔
Margaery Tyrell, I've heard.
在我的允许下
By my leave.
他们知道是我拯救了这座城市 他们知道是我赢下了这场战争
They know I saved the city. They know I won the war.
战争可还没赢呢 史坦尼斯还活着
The war's not won. Not while Stannis lives.
我在黑水河上粉碎了史坦尼斯的军队
I broke Stannis on the Blackwater.
可惜你没能帮上忙 舅舅
Pity you weren't there to help, Uncle.
很抱歉 国王陛下 我当时正忙着呢
My apologies, Your Grace. I was rather busy.
忙着被抓
Busy getting captured.
这就是著名的“兄弟之书”？
So this is the famous "Book of Brothers"?
记录那些伟大的御林铁卫的丰功伟绩
All the great deeds of all the great Kingsguard.
亚瑟·戴恩爵士 拂晓神剑
Ser Arthur Dayne. The Sword of the Morning.
率军攻打御林兄弟会
Led the attack on the Kingswood Brotherhood.
在单打独斗中击败了微笑骑士
Defeated the Smiling Knight in single combat.
“高个”邓肯爵士
Ser Duncan the Tall.
邓肯爵士有整整四页
Four pages for Ser Duncan.
他肯定是个人物
He must have been quite a man.
人们都这么说
So they say.
詹姆·兰尼斯特爵士
Ser Jaime Lannister.
詹姆•兰尼斯特 爵士
作为巴利斯坦·赛尔弥的侍从参与
平定御林兄弟会之战。因战斗勇猛，
年仅十六岁即在战场受封为骑士，
不久被任命为御林铁卫。
君临之战中，弑君伊里斯二世于铁
王座之下。被新国王劳勃•拜拉席恩
赦免。人称弑君者。
看来人们忘了写下你的功绩了呀
Someone forgot to write down all your great deeds.
- 还有的是时间 - 有吗？
- There's still time. - Is there?
对于一个四十岁只有一只手的骑士？
For a 40-year-old knight with one hand?
你凭什么来保护我？
How can you protect me with that?
我现在用左手了 陛下
I use my left hand now, Your Grace.
更加具有挑战性
Makes for more of a contest.
你曾去过弥林吗？
Have you ever been to Meereen?
克拉兹尼大人带我去过几次 陛下
Several times, Your Grace, with Master Kraznys.
然后呢？
And?
据说弥林为了造大金字塔
They say 1,000 slaves died
死了一千个奴隶
building the Great Pyramid of Meereen.
如今一支曾是奴隶的大军
And now an army of former slaves
正向她进军
is marching to her gates.
你觉得善主大人们会害怕么？
You think the Great Masters are worried?
如果他们够聪明就应该害怕 陛下
If they're smart, Your Grace.
你的职责是给军队殿后
You were told to ride at the back of the train.
是的 女王
Yes, my queen.
不过我有要事欲谈
But I need to speak to you about something important.
战略事宜
A matter of strategy.
陛下
Your Grace.
好吧 什么战略事宜？
All right, what is this matter of strategy?
这是一支薄暮玫瑰
A dusk rose.
要不你别骑马了跟在军队后面散步吧
Would you like to walk at the back of the train instead of riding?
这支名为淑女缎带
And this one's called lady's lace.
干脆鞋也脱了光脚走吧
Would you like to walk without shoes?
要统治一方 您必须了解它
You have to know a land to rule it.
植物 河流
Its plants, its rivers,
道路 人民
its roads, its people.
薄暮玫瑰茶可缓解黄热病
Dusk rose tea eases fever.
弥林人都知道这点
Everyone in Meereen knows that.
尤其是专做这种茶的奴隶
Especially the slaves who have to make the tea.
如果你想让他们追随你
If you want them to follow you,
你得融入他们的世界
you have to become a part of their world.
战略
Strategy.
鹰身女妖的黄金
Harpy's Gold.
这种花不能泡茶
No tea from this one.
美丽却有毒
Beautiful but poisonous.
你还真是个投机者
You are a gambler, aren't you?
陛下
Your Grace.
从此处到弥林 每隔一里都以此为标记
There's one on every mile marker between here and Meereen.
到弥林还有几里？
How many miles are there between here and Meereen?
163 陛下
163, Your Grace.
我将下令派遣人马先行 逐一埋葬前方的尸体
I'll tell our men to ride ahead and bury them.
您无须目睹这番景象
You don't need to see this.
我不准你下此命令
You will do no such thing.
我要亲眼看看每一张脸
I will see each and every one of their faces.
埋葬她之前 把项圈拿掉
Remove her collar before you bury her.
她就在那
There she is.
是啊 她就在那
Yes, there she is.
- 所以？ - 你发过誓
- And? - You made a promise.
发誓把史塔克家的闺女还给她母亲 现在她母亲已经死了
To return the Stark girls to their mother who is now dead.
发誓保护她们安全
To keep them safe.
说起艾莉亚·史塔克 自从她父亲被砍头
Well, Arya Stark hasn't been seen
就再也不见她踪影
since her father was killed.
你认为她在哪？ 我打赌她是死了
Where do you think she is? My money's on dead.
死不失为一种安全 你说呢？
There's a certain safety in death, wouldn't you say?
而现下珊莎·史塔克已是珊莎·兰尼斯特
And Sansa Stark is now Sansa Lannister.
情况有点复杂啊
Bit of a complication.
再复杂你也发过誓
A complication does not release you from a vow.
你想让我怎样？绑架我弟妹？
What do you want me to do? Kidnap my sister-in-law?
然后把她带去哪？除了这儿 她在哪儿能更安全？
And take her where? Where would she be safer than here?
看着我的眼睛 告诉我
Look me in the eye and tell me
你真的认为她在君临会安全吗？
that you think she'll be safe in King's Landing.
你确定我们不是亲戚？
Are you sure we're not related?
自从我回来 每个我见到的兰尼斯特
Ever since I've returned, every Lannister I've seen
都对我不依不饶
has been a miserable pain in my ass.
也许你也是个兰尼斯特
Maybe you're a Lannister, too.
就算长得不像 你也有兰尼斯特的头发
You've got the hair for it if not the looks.
别怕
It's all right.
别怕 别怕
It's all right. It's all right.
- 你喝醉了 - 是的
- You're drunk. - Yes.
唐托斯·霍拉德
弄臣
我有的是原因把自己灌醉
I have good reason to be.
我曾是一名骑士 现在成了个弄臣
Once I was a knight. Now I'm only a fool.
您不记得我了？
Don't you know me?
唐托斯爵士 国王的命名日
Ser Dontos. The king's nameday celebration.
对不起 我不该忘记的
I'm sorry. I should have remembered.
您不必抱歉
I can't accept your apology.
也许我成了个弄臣 但因为您 至少我还活着
I may be a fool, but I'm a living fool, thanks to you.
换谁都会出手相救的
Anyone would have done the same.
但是只有您救了我
But only you did.
我永远无法报答您
I can never repay you.
您救了我的命 但是这个
You gave me my life. But this,
这个比我的命还要珍贵
this is worth more than my life.
这是我祖母留给母亲的祖传珠宝
It belonged to my mother and her mother before her.
霍拉德家族也曾强大气派
House Hollard was strong once.
繁荣昌盛
House on the rise.
往昔的荣耀 却只剩下这个了
That's all that's left of those days,
就因为像我这样 悲哀又肥胖的酒鬼
thanks to a few sad, fat drunks like me.
我不能收下这个
I can't take it.
你非常 非常的好心 但是我不能
It's very, very kind of you, but I can't.
我除了这个一无所有
I don't have anything else left.
这就是我的全部身家了
That's all.
收下它 戴上它
Take it. Wear it.
让我的名字从这个世界消失之前
Let my name have one more moment in the sun
哪怕再享有一次荣光也好
before it disappears from the world.
我会骄傲地戴着它 唐托斯爵士
I'll wear it with pride, Ser Dontos.
嗯
Yeah.
桑铎·克里冈
“猎狗”
艾莉亚·史塔克
什么时候我也能有一匹马？
When am I going to get a horse of my own?
小姑娘想要小马了
The little lady wants a pony.
小姑娘想要离你的体臭远一点
The little lady wants away from your stench.
马可不是伸手就有
Horses aren't easy to come by.
就算有了
Even if they were,
你认为我会让你自己骑吗？
you think I'm gonna put you on your own horse?
我就指望着拿你来换几个钱了 还能放你跑了不成？
Watch the only thing of value I've got in the world ride away?
你为什么没有钱？
Why don't you have any money?
你离开乔佛里之前什么都没偷吗？
Didn't you steal anything from Joffrey before you left?
没有
No.
你脑子不怎么好使吧？
You're not very smart, are you?
我不是小偷
I'm not a thief.
你能下得了手杀小孩子
You're fine with murdering little boys,
却高贵得没法行窃？
but thieving is beneath you?
我也有自己的原则
A man's got to have a code.
你认为我会跑掉
You think I'm gonna escape?
我能跑哪去？
Where would I go?
我自己连天黑都撑不到
I'd be dead by nightfall without you.
我家人都不在了 我没有人可以依靠
My family's gone. I've got no one.
你在鹰巢城有个姨妈
You've got an aunt in the Vale.
你的莱莎姨妈有的是钱 我要拿你换赎金
Your rich Aunt Lysa. After I sell you to her,
也许她还能剩不少
maybe she'll have enough left over
给你买匹马 满足你的小愿望
to buy you that pony you want so much.
我饿了 你也饿了
I'm hungry. You're hungry.
五匹马 五个人
Five horses, five men.
饿着肚子我可不好杀这么多人
More than I feel like killing on an empty stomach.
我认识他
I know him.
矮个子那个 他叫波利佛
The small one. His name is Polliver.
是他把我们抓到赫伦堡的
He captured us and took us to Harrenhal.
他杀了罗米
He killed Lommy.
罗米又他妈是个什么东西？
What the fuck's a Lommy?
是我朋友
He was my friend.
波利佛偷了我的剑 刺穿了他的脖子
Polliver stole my sword and put it right through his neck.
他还带着呢
He's still got it.
带着啥？
Got what?
我的剑 缝衣针
My sword Needle.
缝衣针？你连剑都命名
Needle? Of course you named your sword.
很多人都给剑命名的
Lots of people name their swords.
一群娘娘腔
Lots of cunts.
你干什—— 快回来
What are you-- get back here.
那把剑是我哥哥给我的
My brother gave me that sword.
- 快回来 - 他杀了我的朋友
- Get back here. - He killed my friend.
我不管他把你朋友吃了还是如何
I don't care if he ate your friend.
我们不能进去
We're not going in there.
得了吧 别反抗了
Come on, give it up.
过来
Come here.
- 让我摸摸那 - 先别碰她
- Let's have a feel there. - Leave it.
过来
Come here.
求求你 她是个好姑娘
Please, she's a good girl.
闭上嘴巴给我们多倒点酒
Shut your mouth and pour us more ale
心情好的话我们就在这儿干干她 不至于带走
and we may not take her with us when we're done with her.
我认识你
I know you.
这不是猎狗嘛
You're the Hound.
倒点酒给我们的新朋友
Pour our new friend some ale.
什么风把你吹到这么北的地方来了？
What brings you so far north?
波利佛
士兵 效忠于"魔山"
你不也是么
I could ask the same of you.
你们在这干什么？
What are you doing up here?
服从国王的命令守护王国和平呗
Just keeping the king's peace.
没这必要 战争结束了
No need. The war's over.
我听说了 史坦尼斯在黑水河战败
So I've heard. Stannis defeated at the Blackwater.
罗柏·史塔克在孪河城被杀
Robb Stark killed at the Twins.
而我又在干吗呢？
And where am I for all of it?
还不是当你哥哥的狗腿子
Stuck with your brother.
- 无意冒犯 - 我不介意
- Meaning no offense. - None taken.
魔山 他很不错
He's good, the Mountain is.
做着他擅长的事
Best at what he does.
但是天天拷问啊 拷问啊 拷问啊 拷问啊
But torture, torture, torture, torture.
你天天拿锤子折磨人
You spend enough time putting the hammer to people,
慢慢就像木匠做椅子一样
you start to feel like a carpenter making chairs.
乐趣全无了
Drains the fun right out of it.
生活没点乐子怎么成啊？
And what's life without a little fun?
用不着我告诉你怎么找乐子 不是吗？
But I don't need to tell you that, eh?
她还行 我上过更好的
She's all right. I've had better.
跟你说啊
You know what?
你应该跟我们走
You should come with us.
这帮家伙老好了 他们总是藏着点什么东西
His kind, they've always got something hidden away somewhere.
金子 银子 女儿
Gold, silver, more daughters.
只要能撬开他们的嘴 总有好东西
Always something if you know how to make them talk.
从这回君临的路上 这些人有的是
And there's plenty of him between here and King's Landing.
你也能干得很好
You could do well for yourself.
我们已经尝到了甜头
We certainly have been.
我不会回君临的
I'm not going to King's Landing.
好好想想 我们想做什么都成
Think about it. We could do whatever we like
不管去哪
wherever we go.
现在这是国王的颜色了
These are the king's colors.
没人敢档国王的道
No one's standing in his way now.
没人能拦着我们
Which means no one's standing in ours.
去他妈的国王
Fuck the king.
当我听说乔佛里的狗夹起尾巴
When I heard that Joffrey's dog had tucked tail
从黑水河之战逃之夭夭
and run from the Battle of the Blackwater,
我当时还不信
I didn't believe it.
- 可你就在我面前 - 在你面前
- But here you are. - Here I am.
那边的鸡 给我来一只
Bring me one of those chickens.
- 你付得起钱吗？ - 你付钱了吗？
- You got money to pay for it? - You paid for it?
没
No.
但我们是国王的人
But we're the king's men.
那么 你有钱没有？
So, you got money?
一毛钱都没有
Not a penny.
我还是要那只鸡
I'll still take that chicken.
这么说吧
Tell you what.
我们做笔交易
We'll trade you.
我们的一只鸡 换你的一只鸡
One of our little chickens for one of yours.
让我们上上你那朋友
Give us a go at your friend.
洛厄尔喜欢强上野一点儿的姑娘
Lowell there likes them a bit broken in.
你很能扯嘴皮子
You're a talker.
听人扯嘴皮子让我口渴
Listening to talkers makes me thirsty.
啊
Ah.
还让我更饿了
And hungry.
我想来两只鸡了
Think I'll take two chickens.
你好像还没搞清楚情况
You don't seem to understand the situation.
你再从那逼样的烂嘴里
I understand that if any more words
蹦出一个字
come pouring out of your cunt mouth,
我就吃光这屋子里的每只鸡
I'm gonna have to eat every fucking chicken in this room.
你这辈子都为国王而活
You lived your life for the king.
就为了几只鸡去死吗？
You're gonna die for some chickens?
总有人会死
Someone is.
你腿怎么了 小子？
Something wrong with your leg, boy?
什么 你说什么？
What? What do you mean?
能走吗？ 还是得我来背你？
Can you walk? I've got to carry you?
背我？
Carry me?
不错的小剑
Fine little blade.
或许我能用它剔牙
Maybe I'll pick my teeth with it.
衣柜字幕组出品